Jonathan A. Bethune

therenegadeoffunk@gmail.com (070) 4069-4357

Setagaya-ku, Tokyo, Japan

Introduction

I am an experienced software developer and data engineer from New York City.

I have a decade of experience in variety of systems engineering and application development.

My dream is to build software that makes the world a better place.

Education

Bachelor of Science, English Education, New York University

2006

Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, Engineering, Massachusetts Institute of Technology no degree

Master of Information Systems, University of Phoenix 2014

Work History

Software Developer, Knewton, New York City

April 2010 - September 2014

- Wrote application code for Java microservices.
- Created infrastructure deployment and monitoring tools in Python.
- Served for a year as QA Engineer and wrote integration test service.

Lead Systems Engineer, Timehop, New York City

November 2014 - August 2015

- Managed AWS infrastructure including RDS, EC2, and DynamoDB services.
- Served as Site Reliability Engineer responding to alerts and preventing outages.
- · Created various infrastructure tools using Go and Chef.

Senior Devops Engineer, Cloudpassage, San Francisco

August 2015 - Present

- Optimized multiple Cassandra clusters and created tools for big data analysis.
- Improved scalability and helped reduced AWS costs via data model auditing and automation.
- Automated numerous maintenance and deployment tasks using BASH and Chef.

Independent / Open Source Projects / Volunteer Work Remote CS Teaching for Kentucky High School

Fall 2013 - Summer 2014 (Volunteer)

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, BASH, Java, C, C++, Ruby, Scala, Go, Haskell Data Science: Octave, R, Spark, Machine Learning, ELT, Storm

Ops: Unix, AWS, Cassandra, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Chef, Redis,

Docker

Other Skills

Foreign Languages: Japanese, Mandarin, Spanish (basic)

Editing: Copy Editing, Technical Writing, Teaching

Links

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jonathan-bethune-27ba3331

Github: https://github.com/therenegadeoffunk

[†]Source code available at http://github.com/TheRenegadeofFunk/